Julien Zamor

Engineering Manager Tech lead Web Architect

Born 1985-07-16

Address 127 avenue Gambetta

75020 Paris

Phone +33.6.37.29.72.80

Email <u>julienzamor@gmail.com</u>

Twitter <u>@smwhr</u>
LinkedIn <u>LinkedIn Profile</u>

GitHub @smwhr

About Me

I've been a web enthousiast for twenty years, ever since that first website I made during lunch breaks in my high-school library.

I've helped build the internet as much as it helped build me, always with ethical perspective and the desire to make more of the real world.

With an academic background in mathematics and raised by my family in the love of the humanities, I always strive in work environment where hard skills serve culture.

Strong points

Excellent relational skills and empathetic co-worker.

A down-to-earth approach in the (technical) decision making process built on years of experiences of failures and successes.

Curious and avid learner of all things old and new.

Skills

Programming languages

PHP (Expert) Python (Expert) Javascript (Expert) Swift (Advanced) Objective-C (Advanced) Shell (Advanced) Haskell (Advanced curiosity)

Markup Language

XHTML (Expert) CSS4 (Expert) SASS (Expert)

Database and query language

MySQL (Expert) ElasticSearch (Advanced) PostgreSQL (Advanced) GraphQL (Advanced) Redis (Advanced) CouchDB (Advanced) Neo4J (Intermediate)

Other tech skills

Linux sysadmin (Expert) AWS (Expert) Docker (Expert) Kubernetes (Advanced) MS Azure (Advanced) FFMPEG/Video (Advanced)

Business skills

Project Management (7y) Team lead (10y+) Education and mentoring (6y)

Human languages

French (Native) English (Fluent) German (Written)

Experiences

CTO (Founder)

<u>Trois Yaourts</u> November 2013 - Now

- Technical direction for all client projects over a large field of web and mobile technology for a team of 4.
- Technical counseling and external CTO for third parties, including code modernization, hiring test, choice of providers.
- Internal tooling, and dev ops.
- Management and day-to-day business running the company.

Programmation teacher

Epitech Digital Paris

November 2014 - Now

- Logic & Algorithms 1st, 2nd year.
- Industrialization & cloud 2nd, 3rd year.
- PHP Object & Architecture 2nd year.
- Business project mentoring 2nd, 3rd year.

Technical lead - Web platform

My Major Company

January 2012 - October 2013

- Technical choices and liaison with third party provider.
- Team manager on the maintenance and evolution of the new version (new business model).
- Development and maintenance of critical business modules (payment, credit...).

Earlier Experiences

Fullstack web architect

Jiwa (Digiteka then Investisseurs Réunis/Allomusic)

January 2011 - December 2011

Fullstack Web developper

<u>Vodkaster.com</u>

February 2010 - December 2010

Research Internship in cryptography

École Nationale Supérieure des Techniques Avancées

March 2008 - July 2008

Hobbies & extra-skill

- Cinephile.
- Sci-fi reader.
- Occasional indie game developper.
- Father of two (2018, 2020).

Education

M2 Theorical Computer Science

Paris VII - École Normale Supérieure (Ulm) - Paris

- Specialisation: Cryptography of multivariate-systems.

M1 Pure & applied mathematics

Columbia University, New York City

– Major : Algebra & Topology

- Minor : Mathematics of finance

2007 - 2008

2006 - 2007